carbonview.com 2017-09-05

# Privacy | EnsembleIQ

French Text Follows the English

Eagle Operating Corp. d/b/a EnsembleIQ and its subsidiaries (collectively referred to as “Company” or “we”) knows that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. This privacy policy applies to the following websites, as well as the website you are currently accessing (if not on the following list):

• EnsembleIQ: [http://www.EnsembleIQ.com/home](http://www.ensembleiq.com/home)  
• Apparel Magazine: <http://apparel.edgl.com/home>  
• The Canadian Coffee & Tea Show: <http://coffeeteashow.ca/>  
• Canadian Grocer: <http://www.canadiangrocer.com/>  
• Canadian Healthcare Network: <http://www.canadianhealthcarenetwork.ca/> and <http://www.professionsante.ca/>  
• Carbonview Research: <http://www.carbonview.com/>  
• CCentral: <http://ccentral.ca/>  
• Consumer Goods Technology: <http://www.consumergoods.com/>  
• The Convenience U Carwacs Show: <http://calgary.convenienceu.ca/>  
• Convenience Store News: <http://www.csnews.com/>  
• Convenience Store News for Single Store Owners: <http://www.csnews.com/single-store-owner>  
• EKN Research: <http://eknresearch.com/>  
• FoodBiz: <http://foodbiz.ca/>  
• The Gourmet Retailer: <http://www.gourmetretailer.com/>  
• Hospitality Technology: <http://hospitalitytechnology.edgl.com/home>  
• Le Salon des Dépanneurs: <http://salondec.com/>  
• Monday Report on Retailers: <http://www.mondayreport.ca/>  
• Path to Purchase Institute: <https://p2pi.org/>  
• Path to Purchase Expo: <http://www.path2purchaseexpo.com/>  
• Shopper Marketing: <http://www.shoppermarketingmag.com/home/>  
• Pharmacy U: <http://pharmacyu.ca/>  
• Progressive Grocer: <http://www.progressivegrocer.com/>  
• RIS News: <http://www.risnews.com/>  
• Retail Leader: <http://www.retailleader.com/>  
• Retail Buyers: <http://retailbuyers.net/>  
• Shopper Marketing Summit: <http://www.shoppersummit.com/>  
• Store Brands: <http://www.storebrands.info/>  
• StratConn: <http://www.stratconn.org/>  
• Top Women in Grocery: <http://www.topwomeningrocery.progressivegrocer.com/>

Amendments to this privacy policy will be posted at this URL and will be effective when posted. Your continued use of any of our websites following the posting of any amendment, modification or change shall constitute your acceptance thereof. By visiting the present website or any of the foregoing websites, you are accepting the practices described in this privacy policy.

**WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DO WE GATHER?**

• We receive and store any information you enter on our websites or provide to us in any other way. You can choose not to provide certain information, but then you might not be able to take advantage of many of our features.  
• We may also receive information about you from other sources and add it to your account information. This information might be public information or data you provided with necessary and proper permissions.  
• We use the information that we gather for such purposes as responding to your requests, customizing future visits for you, improving our online store, notifying you of new products and services, conducting market research, and otherwise communicating with you.  
• We participate in multiple ad networks. When you visit our websites, these networks place a cookie on your browser. These cookies contain no Personally Identifiable Information (PII). They identify you as a visitor to our website, and allow us or our clients to display relevant advertising to you both on our site, and after you leave our site on ad placements throughout the ad networks’ participating websites. To opt out of the targeted advertising provided by EnsembleIQ, please visit the National Advertising Initiative opt-out page: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.  
• We gather date, time, certain information about a user's browser and system or device configuration and capabilities, navigation history and IP address for all visitors to our websites.  
We use this information for our internal audit log, for trend analysis and system administration, and to gather broad information about our audiences and their geographic locations. Non-personal demographic and profile data is used to tailor your experience at our websites, showing you content we think might be of interested to you. This information may also be shared with advertisers on an aggregate and/or non-personal basis.  
• Visitors to EnsembleIQ websites should understand that by using these websites, information may be collected about them via cookies placed on their hard drive to enhance or customize the experience. By visiting any of our websites, you give us permission for the use of cookies for this purpose.  
• Other third party ad servers or ad networks may also use cookies to track users’ activities on this website to measure advertisement effectiveness, to deliver targeted advertising, or for other reasons. We are not responsible for the use of information obtained or shown to visitors as a result of the data collected by third party advertisers.  
• We use cookies and common data collection technologies, including associated web beacons and transparent GIFs associated with cookies, on our newsletters and in our email campaigns to collect information both on an aggregate and individual basis.

**HOW WE USE INFORMATION ABOUT YOU**

• We share customer information with trusted agents and partners who work to perform functions on our behalf, including data processing, order and publication fulfillment, sending postal mail and e-mail, processing credit card payments, providing customer service, and providing marketing assistance (including direct and targeted marketing).  
• We may send offers on behalf of our carefully selected business partners, or you may receive offers directly from our business partners. Our business partners include all of our affiliated companies as well as other selected businesses with which we have a relationship and which have agreed to adhere to our strict standards for providing quality products and services, responding to your needs, and protecting customer information. Keep in mind that if you take advantage of an offer from an EnsembleIQ business partner and become their customer, they may independently wish to send offers to you. In this case, you will need to inform them separately if you wish to decline receiving future offers from them.  
• Due to the technology behind our websites, your personal information may also be shared with designated website partners in order to reduce the number of registrations you need to make on our websites. This is an effort to make use of our websites more convenient for you.  
• We may use your IP Address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Websites. We may also use your IP Address to help identify possible misuse or misappropriation of passwords and members-only access  
• We use your information to enhance your website experience, including member-only content or discounts, and to deliver or display personalized content that matches your professional goals and responsibilities.  
• We use your information to contact you, either by online electronic communication (such as e-mail), or by regular mail or telephone, including to offer you opportunities to connect directly with your peers and with sellers of products or services that may be of interest to you.  
• We may also invite you to join our communities via third party social and professional networking sites.  
• We may use your information any other purpose that we tell you about when you give us the information or to which you consent.  
• We release customer information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with law; enforce or apply our conditions of use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of the Company, our users, or others.  
• In the event of a sale of all or part of one of our businesses, we may share customer information related to that business as part of the transaction.

**E-COMMERCE TRANSACTIONS**

Payment information that is collected by us and/or our payment processor is used to check your purchasing qualifications and to bill you for products and services. When you place an order online with us, your personal details and credit card information are scrambled using industry-standard SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) encryption technology before being sent over the Internet. Although we cannot guarantee encryption or the privacy of your personal details and credit card information, SSL makes it very difficult for your information to be stolen or intercepted while being transferred. Our credit card transactions are maintained by several companies. All information sent to those companies is encrypted, which will protect it against disclosure to third parties. When we receive your order, it is kept encrypted until our credit card processor is ready to process it. When you conduct a transaction with a third party to whom you are linked from one of our websites, you should review such vendor's policy regarding e-commerce transactions on their website. The Institute is not responsible for products and services transactions that are consummated at third party websites.

**PUBLIC FORUMS**

Our Websites may make public chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to you from time to time. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information.

**WHAT CHOICES DO I HAVE?**

• Connecting directly with other companies for marketing purposes. In addition to providing you with our own editorial content, we offer you the opportunity to access others’ branded content and product information. When you choose to take advantage of that content or information, you choose to have your name and contact details transferred directly to that other company. We will provide your contact information to another company or companies when you choose to:  
• Sign-in to one of our online properties to access registration-required, or “gated” content. Access to gated resources provided or sponsored by another company is contingent on your agreement that your contact details may be shared with the other company. We may track your interest in that company’s content or our own content over time and disclose your ongoing interest to that company;  
• Register for a specific webcast, online event, website, newsletter, or other offering which is sponsored or co-sponsored by another company or companies;  
• Attend one of our face-to-face events. Exhibitors may be given an attendance list for the event. A sponsor of a special, sponsored conference session will also be given information about you if you choose to attend that company’s session. Your future interaction with online content from an exhibitor or sponsor to whom you provided your contact data to may also be tracked and disclosed to that exhibitor or sponsor.  
• Receiving email marketing messages from us. You may opt-out of our email marketing lists by following the directions at the bottom of our promotional emails and newsletters. Please note that we have a number of brands and promotional email vehicles and allow you to opt-out selectively. From select websites, you may also view and modify all of your email preferences using your preferences page available on each website. To remove a specific email address from all email marketing from the Company, you may also send a request to [info@ensembleIQ.com](mailto:info@ensembleIQ.com).  
• Whether your account information is up to date. Please help us keep your account information up to date. You may manage or update your online registration and print subscriptions by following the link to your preference page after you have logged on to any EnsembleIQ website.  
• Participation in Ad Networks. If you do not want to view targeted advertisements on our site or through our participating ad networks, please opt out at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.  
• Forward to a Colleague: While visiting our websites or reading our newsletters and promotional emails you may choose to use the "Forward to a Colleague" tool which allows you to inform a colleague about content of interest to you. The information you provide will be used to send a one-time email to your colleague, inviting them to our website(s). We will not add your colleague to a mailing list and will not send them further email unless they choose to receive such communications from us. When using the "Forward to a Colleague" tool you are contacting your colleague directly and as such you acknowledge that you are responsible for this correspondence and not the Company. If you provide us with personal information concerning another individual (such as an email address), you represent and warrant that you have obtained all necessary consents from that individual to enable us to use that personal information for the identified purpose.

**MORE INFORMATION ABOUT COOKIES**

You also have choices about cookies: We place cookies that identify you, or allow third parties to do so on our behalf, for the following purposes: • To recognize you automatically when you return to a gated website.  
• To understand your interests in content, both our own and that of other companies, on our websites.  
• To control access to gated online events such as webcasts.  
• To provide automatic access to our gated content via email communications sent directly to you.

You may use the tools in your browser to decline, disable, or delete any cookies.

If you decline, disable, or delete the session cookie for one of our gated websites you may remain on the website but you will not be able to access or download any gated content or access your personalized online preferences page. You must also accept the session cookie used to manage access to registration-only online events for the duration of your participation.

**HOW SECURE IS INFORMATION ABOUT ME?**

We take appropriate and industry-standard administrative, technical, and physical measures to protect your personal information against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction. While we do work hard to protect your privacy, no method of security is 100% effective and we cannot be responsible for the actions of those who may gain unauthorized access to your personal information. ENSEMBLEIQ MAKES NO WARRANTIES, EXPRESS, IMPLIED OR OTHERWISE AS TO THE ULTIMATE EFFECTIVENESS OF THESE MEASURES. You remain responsible for protecting your sign-in credentials and for the security of information in transit to us over the Internet.

We also take reasonable and appropriate steps to ensure that your personal information is accurate, complete, and current; however we depend upon you to update or correct your information whenever necessary.

• We work to protect the security of your financial information during e-commerce transmissions by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input.  
We reveal only the nameplate of your credit card (Visa, MasterCard, American Express) when confirming an order. Of course, we transmit the entire credit card number to the appropriate credit card company or payment processor during order processing.

**CONTESTS AND SWEEPSTAKES**

When we run a contest or sweepstakes relating to our websites, it will be accompanied by a set of rules. The rules, available in every applicable email invitation and/or entry webpage for each contest or sweepstakes, specify how the information gathered from you for entry will be used and disclosed (if it is different than as described in this privacy policy). In conjunction with your entry in such contest or sweepstakes, personally identifiable information will be collected only if you voluntarily submit it.

**CONDITIONS OF USE, NOTICES, AND REVISIONS**

If you choose to visit EnsembleIQ’s website(s), your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this privacy policy and our terms and conditions of service, separately available on all of our websites, including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, and application of appropriate laws. If you have any concern about privacy at EnsembleIQ’s website(s), please email a thorough description to us at [info@ensembleIQ.com](mailto:info@ensembleIQ.com), and we will try to resolve it. Our industry changes constantly. This privacy policy and our terms and conditions of service will change also, and use of information that we gather now is subject to the privacy policy in effect at the time of use.

**CHILDREN'S GUIDELINES**

Our products, services, events, and offerings are directed to professionals only. No one under the age of 13 is eligible to use our websites and should not provide any personal information. As a practice, we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. In the event that we learn that we have collected information from a child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will promptly delete this information from our database.

**YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of EnsembleIQ who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of their personally identifiable information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [info@ensembleIQ.com](mailto:info@ensembleIQ.com) specifying that you seek your “California Customer Choice Notice.” Please allow thirty days for a response.

**CONTACTING US**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, the practices of EnsembleIQ with respect to personal information, or your dealings with our web properties, you may email client services at [info@ensembleIQ.com](mailto:info@ensembleIQ.com), call us at 224-632-8200, or write to:  
EnsembleIQ Client Services  
Attn.: Privacy Statement  
8550 W. Bryn Mawr Ave.  
Ste. 200  
Chicago, IL 60631  
USA  
Ph: +1 773-992-4450  
Fax: +1 773-992-4455

* * *

**POLITIQUE DE CONFIDENTIALITÉ**

Date d’entrée en vigueur : 12 janvier 2017

Eagle Operating Corp. d / b / a EnsembleIQ et ses filiales (collectivement désignées sous le nom de « Société » ou « nous ») savent que vous vous souciez de l’utilisation et du partage de vos informations et apprécions votre confiance en nous pour ce faire avec grand soin. Cette politique de confidentialité s’applique aux sites Web suivants, ainsi qu’au site Web auquel vous accédez actuellement (si ce n’est sur la liste suivante):

• EnsembleIQ: [http://www.EnsembleIQ.com/home](http://www.ensembleiq.com/home)  
• Apparel Magazine: <http://apparel.edgl.com/home>  
• The Canadian Coffee & Tea Show: <http://coffeeteashow.ca/>  
• Canadian Grocer: <http://www.canadiangrocer.com/>  
• Canadian Healthcare Network: <http://www.canadianhealthcarenetwork.ca/> and <http://www.professionsante.ca/>  
• Carbonview Research: <http://www.carbonview.com/>  
• CCentral: <http://ccentral.ca/>  
• Consumer Goods Technology: <http://www.consumergoods.com/>  
• The Convenience U Carwacs Show: <http://calgary.convenienceu.ca/>  
• Convenience Store News: <http://www.csnews.com/>  
• Convenience Store News for Single Store Owners: <http://www.csnews.com/single-store-owner>  
• EKN Research: <http://eknresearch.com/>  
• FoodBiz: <http://foodbiz.ca/>  
• The Gourmet Retailer: <http://www.gourmetretailer.com/>  
• Hospitality Technology: <http://hospitalitytechnology.edgl.com/home>  
• Le Salon des Dépanneurs: <http://salondec.com/>  
• Monday Report on Retailers: <http://www.mondayreport.ca/>  
• Path to Purchase Institute: <https://p2pi.org/>  
• Path to Purchase Expo: <http://www.path2purchaseexpo.com/>  
• Shopper Marketing: <http://www.shoppermarketingmag.com/home/>  
• Pharmacy U: <http://pharmacyu.ca/>  
• Progressive Grocer: <http://www.progressivegrocer.com/>  
• RIS News: <http://www.risnews.com/>  
• Retail Leader: <http://www.retailleader.com/>  
• Retail Buyers: <http://retailbuyers.net/>  
• Shopper Marketing Summit: <http://www.shoppersummit.com/>  
• Store Brands: <http://www.storebrands.info/>  
• StratConn: <http://www.stratconn.org/>  
• Top Women in Grocery: <http://www.topwomeningrocery.progressivegrocer.com/>

Les modifications apportées à cette politique de confidentialité seront affichées à cette adresse et entreront en vigueur à partir de cette date. Votre continuité concernant l’utilisation de l’un de nos sites Web suite à l’affichage d’une modification, de tout avenant ou changement constitue votre acceptation. En visitant le présent site Web ou l’un des sites Web précédents, vous acceptez les pratiques décrites dans cette politique de confidentialité.

**QUELS SONT LES RENSEIGNEMENTS PERSONNELS QUE NOUS RASSEMBLONS?**

• Nous recevons et stockons toutes les informations que vous entrez sur nos sites Web ou ceux qui nous alimentent de quelque manière. Vous pouvez choisir de ne pas fournir certaines informations, mais vous pourriez ne pas être en mesure de profiter d’un bon nombre de nos fonctionnalités.  
• Nous pouvons également recevoir des informations vous concernant provenant d’autres sources et les incorporer aux informations de votre compte. Ces informations peuvent être publiques ou encore des données que vous avez fournies et dûment autorisées.  
• Nous utilisons les informations que nous recueillons à des fins telles que répondre à vos demandes, personnaliser vos visites futures, améliorer notre boutique en ligne, vous informer de nouveaux produits et services, mener des études de marché et communiquer autrement avec vous.  
• Nous participons de plusieurs réseaux publicitaires. Lorsque vous visitez nos sites Web, ces réseaux installent un cookie sur votre navigateur. Ces cookies ne contiennent aucune information personnelle identifiable (PII). Ils vous identifient en tant que visiteur de notre site Web et nous permettent, ou à nos clients, de vous offrir une publicité pertinente sur notre site et après l’avoir quitté d’orienter les placements publicitaires sur les sites Web participants des réseaux annonceurs. Pour vous désinscrire de la publicité ciblée fournie par EnsembleIQ, veuillez visiter la page d’exclusion de la National Advertising Initiative: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>  
• Nous recueillons la date, l’heure, certaines informations sur le navigateur d’un utilisateur, ainsi que la configuration et les capacités du système ou du périphérique, l’historique de navigation et l’adresse IP de tous les visiteurs de nos sites Web. Nous utilisons ces informations pour notre journal d’audit interne, pour l’analyse des tendances et l’administration du système, et pour recueillir de plus amples informations sur nos auditoires et leurs emplacements géographiques. Des données démographiques et de profil non personnelles sont utilisées pour personnaliser votre expérience sur nos sites Web, en vous montrant le contenu que nous pensons pouvoir vous intéresser. Ces informations peuvent également être partagées avec les annonceurs en mode agrégé ou non personnel.  
• Les visiteurs des sites Web EnsembleIQ doivent comprendre qu’en utilisant ces sites Web, des informations peuvent être recueillies à leur sujet au moyen de cookies installés sur leur disque dur afin d’améliorer ou personnaliser leur expérience. En visitant l’un de nos sites Web, vous nous autorisez à utiliser des cookies à cette fin.  
• D’autres serveurs publicitaires tiers ou réseaux publicitaires utilisent également des cookies pour suivre les activités des utilisateurs sur ce site Web afin de mesurer l’efficacité de la publicité, de diffuser de la publicité ciblée ou pour d’autres raisons. Nous ne sommes pas responsables de l’utilisation des informations obtenues ou présentées aux visiteurs à la suite des données recueillies par des annonceurs tiers.  
• Nous utilisons des cookies et des technologies courantes de collecte de données, y compris balises web et GIF transparents associés à ces cookies, dans nos bulletins d’information et nos campagnes de courriel pour rassembler des informations à niveau global et individuel.

**COMMENT UTILISONS-NOUS VOS INFORMATIONS?**

• Nous partageons les informations sur les clients avec des agents et des partenaires de confiance qui travaillent pour effectuer des tâches en notre nom, notamment le traitement des données, l’exécution des commandes et des publications, l’envoi de courrier postal et courriels, le traitement des paiements par carte de crédit, le service à la clientèle et l’assistance commerciale (commercialisation directe et ciblée).  
• Nous pouvons envoyer des offres pour le compte de nos partenaires d’affaires soigneusement sélectionnés, ou bien vous pouvez recevoir des offres provenant directement de ces derniers. Nos partenaires commerciaux incluent toutes nos sociétés affiliées ainsi que d’autres entreprises sélectionnées avec lesquelles nous sommes en rapport et qui ont accepté de respecter nos normes strictes afin d’offrir des produits et des services de qualité, répondre à vos besoins et protéger l’information des clients. N’oubliez pas que si vous profitez d’une offre d’un partenaire d’EnsembleIQ et que vous devenez client, ils auront le droit de vous envoyer des offres par eux-mêmes. Dans ce cas, vous devrez les informer séparément que vous ne souhaitez pas recevoir d’offres futures de leur part.  
• Grâce à la technologie de nos sites Web, vos renseignements personnels peuvent également être partagés avec des partenaires de sites Web désignés, afin de faciliter votre accès sur nos sites. Ceci dans l’intention de rendre nos sites plus faciles à naviguer.  
• Nous pouvons également utiliser votre adresse IP pour diagnostiquer des problèmes avec notre serveur et pour administrer nos sites Web. Nous pouvons aussi utiliser votre adresse IP pour identifier d’éventuels abus ou détournements de mots de passe et accès réservé aux membres  
• Nous utilisons vos informations pour améliorer votre expérience Web, notamment le contenu réservé aux membres ou les remises, et pour offrir ou afficher un matériel personnalisé qui corresponde à vos responsabilités et objectifs professionnels.  
• Nous utilisons vos informations pour communiquer avec vous, soit par voie numérique (par exemple, par courriel), soit par courrier ou par téléphone, notamment pour vous offrir la possibilité de communiquer directement avec vos pairs et avec les vendeurs de produits ou de services qui pourraient s’intéresser à vous.  
• Nous pouvons également vous inviter à rejoindre nos communautés par l’entremise de réseaux sociaux et professionnels tiers.  
• Nous pouvons en outre utiliser vos informations à toute autre fin consentie et autorisée par vous-même.  
• Nous publions des informations sur les clients lorsque nous croyons que leur diffusion est appropriée et conforme à la loi, renforce ou s’applique à nos conditions d’utilisation et autres accords, ou protège les droits, la propriété et la sécurité de la Société, de nos utilisateurs ou d’autres personnes.  
• En cas de vente totale ou partielle de nos activités, nous pouvons partager les renseignements sur les clients liés à l’entreprise dans le cadre de la transaction.

**TRANSACTIONS COMMERCIALES ÉLECTRONIQUES**

Les informations de paiement que nous recueillions ou notre processeur de paiement sont utilisés pour vérifier vos qualifications d’achat et pour vous facturer les produits et services. Lorsque vous passez une commande en ligne avec nous, vos données personnelles et vos informations de carte de crédit sont brouillées au moyen de la technologie de cryptage SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) standard de l’industrie avant d’être envoyées sur Internet. Bien que nous ne puissions garantir le cryptage ou la confidentialité de vos données personnelles et de vos informations de carte de crédit, SSL rend très difficile le vol ou l’interception de vos informations lors du transfert. Nos transactions par carte de crédit sont gérées par plusieurs sociétés. Toutes les informations envoyées à ces entreprises sont chiffrées, ce qui les protège contre leur divulgation à des tiers. Lorsque nous recevons votre commande, elle est conservée cryptée jusqu’à ce que notre processeur de carte de crédit soit prêt à la traiter. Lorsque vous effectuez une transaction avec un tiers auquel vous êtes lié à partir de l’un de nos sites Web, nous vous recommandons de consulter la politique de ce fournisseur relative aux transactions de commerce électronique sur son site Web. L’Institut n’est pas responsable des transactions de produits et services effectuées sur des sites Web de tiers.

**FORUMS PUBLICS**

Nos sites Web peuvent de temps à autre mettre à votre disposition des salles de discussion publiques, des forums, des bulletins électroniques ou des groupes d’actualités. N’oubliez pas que toute information divulguée dans ces domaines devient une information publique et que vous devez faire preuve de prudence à l’heure de divulguer des renseignements personnels.

**QUELS SONT LES CHOIX POSSIBLES?**

• Connexion directe avec d’autres sociétés à des fins de commerciales. Outre fournir notre propre contenu éditorial, nous vous offrons la possibilité d’accéder au contenu d’autres marques et aux informations sur leurs produits. Lorsque vous choisissez ce contenu ou ces informations, vous choisissez d’envoyer directement votre nom et vos coordonnées à cette autre société. Nous fournirons vos coordonnées à une ou plusieurs entreprises lorsque vous choisissez de :  
• Vous connecter à l’un de nos domaines en ligne pour accéder à la demande d’information requise pour l’inscription ou l’accès au contenu réservé. L’accès à des ressources réservées fournies ou parrainées par une autre société dépend de votre accord quant au partage de vos coordonnées avec l’autre société. Nous serons alors en mesure de suivre votre intérêt dans le contenu de cette société ou notre propre contenu au fil du temps et de le divulguer à cette société;  
• Vous inscrire à une diffusion Web, à un événement en ligne, à un site Web, à un bulletin d’information ou à toute offre parrainée ou coparrainée par une ou plusieurs autres sociétés;  
• Assister à l’un de nos événements de rencontre en personne. Les exposants peuvent recevoir une liste de présence pour l’événement. Le commanditaire d’une session spéciale de conférence commanditée recevra également des renseignements vous concernant si vous choisissez d’assister à la session de cette société. Votre interaction future avec le contenu en ligne d’un exposant ou d’un commanditaire auquel vous avez fourni vos coordonnées peut également être suivie et divulguée à cet exposant ou à ce commanditaire.  
• Recevoir des annonces publicitaires par courriel de notre part. Vous pouvez choisir de ne pas participer à nos listes de diffusion par courriel en suivant les instructions figurant au bas de ceux-ci ou des bulletins d’information promotionnels. Veuillez noter que nous disposons d’un certain nombre de marques et de véhicules promotionnels de communication et que vous pouvez vous désengager de manière sélective. Sur certains sites Web, vous pouvez également afficher et modifier toutes vos préférences de courriel sur votre profil personnel disponible sur chaque site. Pour supprimer une adresse courriel spécifique de tout envoi promotionnel de la Société, veuillez envoyer une demande à [info@ensembleIQ.com](mailto:info@ensembleIQ.com).  
• Même si vos informations de compte sont à jour. Veuillez nous aider à conserver leur fraîcheur. Vous pouvez gérer ou mettre à jour vos abonnements en ligne et imprimer vos inscriptions en suivant le lien vers votre page de préférences après avoir ouvert une session sur un site Web EnsembleIQ.  
• Participation aux réseaux publicitaires. Si vous ne souhaitez pas voir de publicités ciblées sur notre site ou par l’intermédiaire de nos réseaux publicitaires participants, veuillez y renoncer sur <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.  
• Transmettre à un collègue : En visitant nos sites Web ou en lisant nos bulletins et courriels promotionnels, vous pouvez choisir d’utiliser l’outil « Transmettre à un collègue » qui vous permet d’informer un collègue du contenu qui vous intéresse. Les informations que vous fournissez seront utilisées pour envoyer un courriel unique à votre collègue, l’invitant sur notre/nos site(s) Web (s). Nous n’ajouterons pas votre collègue à une liste de diffusion et nous ne lui enverrons pas d’autres courriels, à moins qu’il ne choisisse de recevoir ces communications de notre part. Lorsque vous utilisez l’outil « Transmettre à un collègue », vous communiquez directement avec votre collègue et, en tant que tel, vous reconnaissez que vous êtes responsable de cette correspondance et non la Société. Si vous nous fournissez des renseignements personnels concernant une autre personne (telle qu’une adresse courriel), vous déclarez et garantissez que vous avez obtenu tous les consentements nécessaires de cette personne pour nous permettre d’utiliser lesdits renseignements à des fins précisées.

**EN SAVOIR PLUS SUR LES COOKIES**

Vous avez le choix concernant les cookies : Nous installons des cookies qui vous identifient ou qui permettent à des tiers de le faire en notre nom aux fins suivantes :  
• Pour vous reconnaître automatiquement lorsque vous revenez sur un site Web que vous avez quitté.  
• Pour comprendre vos intérêts dans les contenus, à la fois le nôtre et celui d’autres sociétés, sur nos sites Web.  
• Pour contrôler l’accès aux événements en ligne restreints tels que les émissions Web.  
• Fournir un accès automatique à notre contenu restreint via les communications par courriel qui vous sont envoyées directement.

Vous pouvez utiliser les outils de votre navigateur pour refuser, désactiver ou supprimer des cookies.

Si vous refusez, désactivez ou supprimez le cookie de session pour l’un de nos sites Web restreints, vous pourrez rester sur ce dernier , mais sans pouvoir accéder à ou télécharger certain contenu ou encore accéder à votre page de préférences en ligne personnalisée. Vous êtes également tenu d’accepter le cookie de session utilisé pour gérer l’accès aux événements en ligne, uniquement pour la durée de votre participation.

**DANS QUELLE MESURE MES INFORMATIONS SONT-ELLES PRÉSERVÉES?**

Nous prenons des mesures administratives, techniques et physiques appropriées et standardisées visant à protéger vos informations personnelles contre tout accès non autorisé, toute altération, divulgation ou destruction. Bien que nous travaillions dur pour protéger votre vie privée, aucune méthode de sécurité n’est efficace à 100 % et nous ne pouvons pas être responsables des actions de ceux qui sont susceptibles d’obtenir un accès non autorisé à vos informations personnelles. ENSEMBLEIQ N’OFFRE AUCUNE GARANTIE, EXPRESSE, IMPLICITE OU AUTRE QUANT À L’EFFICACITÉ ULTIME DE CES MESURES. Vous demeurez responsable de la protection de vos informations d’identification et de la sécurité de celles se trouvant en transit sur Internet.

Nous prenons également des mesures raisonnables et appropriées pour garantir l’exactitude et actualisation de vos renseignements personnels; cependant nous dépendons de vous quant à la correction ou mise à jour de telles informations chaque fois que nécessaire.

• Nous travaillons pour protéger la sécurité de vos informations financières lors des transmissions de commerce électronique au moyen du logiciel SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) qui crypte les informations que vous entrez. Nous ne révélons que la plaque signalétique de votre carte de crédit (Visa, MasterCard, American Express) lors de la confirmation d’une commande. Bien sûr, nous transmettons le numéro de carte de crédit entier à la société de carte de crédit appropriée ou processeur de paiement au moment du traitement des commandes.

**CONCOURS ET TIRAGES AU SORT**

Lorsque nous organisons un concours ou un tirage au sort sur nos sites Web, il sera accompagné d’un ensemble de règles. Les règles, disponibles dans chaque invitation électronique ou page Web d’entrée pour chaque concours ou tirage au sort, précisent comment vos informations personnelles seront utilisées et divulguées (ou si la méthode diffère de celle décrite dans la présente politique de confidentialité). Conjointement à votre participation à un tel concours ou tirage au sort, les informations personnelles ne seront recueillies que si vous y consentez volontairement.

**CONDITIONS D’UTILISATION, NOTIFICATIONS ET RÉVISIONS**

Si vous choisissez de visiter le site Web EnsembleIQ, votre visite et tout différend relatifs à la vie privée sont soumis à la présente politique de confidentialité et à nos conditions générales de service, disponibles séparément sur tous nos sites Web, notamment les limites des dommages, l’arbitrage des différends et l’application des lois appropriées. Si vous avez des inquiétudes au sujet de la vie privée relatives au (x) site (s) EnsembleIQ, envoyez-nous une description détaillée à [info@ensembleIQ.com](mailto:info@ensembleIQ.com), et nous nous efforcerons de les résoudre. Notre industrie est en constante évolution. Cette politique de confidentialité et nos conditions générales de service le sont aussi et l’utilisation des renseignements que nous recueillons maintenant est assujettie à la politique de confidentialité en vigueur au moment de l’utilisation.

**LIGNES DIRECTRICES CONCERNANT LES ENFANTS**

Nos produits, services, événements et offres sont réservés aux professionnels. Toute personne âgée de moins de 13 ans n’est pas autorisée à utiliser nos sites Web et ne doit fournir aucun renseignement personnel. Dans la pratique, nous ne recueillons pas sciemment d’informations personnelles identifiables auprès d’enfants de moins de 13 ans. Si nous apprenons que nous avons recueilli des informations auprès d’un enfant de moins de 13 ans sans l’assurance du consentement de ses parents, nous supprimerons rapidement cette information de notre base de données.

**VOTRE DROIT À LA VIE PRIVÉE EN CALIFORNIE**

La section 1798.83 du Code civil de Californie permet aux clients de EnsembleIQ résidant en Californie de solliciter certaines informations concernant la divulgation de leurs renseignements personnels à des tiers à des fins de commercialisation directe. Pour ce faire, veuillez envoyer un courriel à [info@ensembleIQ.com](mailto:info@ensembleIQ.com) en précisant que vous demandez votre « notification de choix du client en Californie. » Veuillez patienter trente jours pour une réponse.

**SE COMMUNIQUER AVEC NOUS**

Si vous avez des questions concernant cette politique de confidentialité, les pratiques d’EnsembleIQ en ce qui concerne les renseignements personnels ou vos rapports avec nos domaines Web, vous pouvez communiquer avec le service clientèle à [info@ensembleIQ.com](mailto:info@ensembleIQ.com), nous appeler au 224-632-8200, ou nous écrire à :  
Service Clientèle EnsembleIQ  
À l’intention de : Déclaration de confidentialité  
8550 W. Bryn Mawr Ave.  
Ste. 200  
Chicago, IL 60631  
USA  
Tél : +1773-992-4450  
Télécopieur : +1773-992-4455
